太好了
Thank God for that.
如果再要我吃金橘 我会吐的
If I have to eat another kumquat, I'll throw up.
我差点被砸死了
I was nearly killed!
要让人修补一下
You need to get that fixed.
我们没钱请人来修
We haven't got any money to get it fixed.
大爆炸
Oh, big boom!
或者用英语说
Mm, or as we say in English,
就是"vadg-galoop"
vadg-galoop.
拉里 一门语言就够难学了
Larry, It's difficult enough to
你还要给她编词
learn a language without making words up!
"Vadg-galoop"
Vadg-galoop.
等她什么时候不讨厌我了 就不编了
I'll stop when she stops hating me.
看 飞龙科蜥蜴
Look! An agama!
西奥说他们生气的时候皮肤会变暗
Theo says their skin darkens when they're upset.
格里 下山 去找斯皮罗斯
Gerry, run down, find Spiros.
告诉他让房东来帮帮我们 格里
Tell him to beg the landlord to help us. Gerry!
- 过来 - 格里
- Come here! - Gerry!
它逃了
It's escaping!
"Peenygrip" 握紧
Peenygrip. Peenygrip. Grip.
"Peenygreep"
Peenygreep.
- "Peenygreep" - 是的
- Peenygreep. - Yes.
马戈 去找斯皮罗斯 还有...
Margo, go and find Spiros and...
我不能出门
I can't leave the house.
马克斯说他会来一趟
Max said he'd be dropping by.
来找我 不是你
To see me, not you.
他跟你说过
Did he tell you how much
有多喜欢你起伏的胸部吗
he loved the rise and fall of your breasts?
拜
Bye!
好吧
Right.
我自己去找
I'll do it myself!
德雷尔一家 第一季 第二集
德雷尔太太 对不起
Mrs Durrells, I'm sorry.
你欠房东租金 所以他不帮你维修了
The landlord will do no more repairs because you owe him rent.
但是等钱从英格兰汇来 我就可以付给他了
But I'll pay him when the money finally comes in from England.
- 你这钱等了多久 - 三周吧
- How long you wait for your money? - Oh... Three weeks.
没有多少钱 就是我的遗孀抚恤金
It's not very much. It's just my widow's pension.
应该是滞留在银行了
It just seems to be held up at the bank.
银行都那副德行
Those bank son-of-a-bitches!
上车 德雷尔太太
Mrs Durrells, get in the car.
你觉得德雷尔小姐是从英国来的
You think Miss Durrell came from England
就可以趁火打劫吗
to be robbed?
她本可以去西班牙的
Eh? She could have gone to Spain!
我再说一遍 去找她的钱
Tha xanapo! Find her money!
他们需要多弄点路灯
They need more street lamps.
所以才要星星
That's what the stars are for.
# 清晨 清晨 #
C'est matin, c'est matin
# 阳光普照 #
When the sun is shining
# 清晨 清晨 #
C'est matin, c'est matin
# 只剩呜咽 #
I only feel like whining
# 清晨 清晨 #
C'est matin, c'est matin
马克斯
Max!
嘿 拉里 我是马克斯
Hey, Larry! It's Max!
- 我是唐纳德 - 还有唐纳德
- And Donald. - And Donald!
但主要是马克斯
But mainly Max.
# 月光沉醉于岸 #
Moonlight drinking upon the shore
# 那就是星星的意义 星星的意义 #
That's what the stars are for, the stars are for!
走开
Bugger off!
# 清晨 只剩... #
C'est matin, I only feel like...
- 你好啊 拉里 - 开门 - 进来
- Hello, Larry. - Open up! - Come in.
- 我们是来吃东西的 - 万岁
- We come for refreshment. - Hooray.
我们一点酒和食物都没有了
We haven't got any booze or food.
万岁...
Hooray...
- 等等 你说什么 - 我们破产了
- Wait. What? - We're broke.
我们全靠吃该死的金橘为生
We're living on bloody kumquats.
- 金什么 - 橘
- Kum-whats? - Quats.
你穿的是什么玩意
What the hell are you nearly wearing?
让我们去镇上喝点茴香烈酒
Let's go into town to get some ouzo.
- 好主意 - 我要留下和马戈说说话
- Good idea. - I'm gonna stay and chat with Margo.
不... 我和你们一起走
No... I'll come with you.
argy-bargy在英式英语中意思为争辩 这里取马戈打头字母合并为一个词
马吵吵 你留下 好好睡个美容觉
Margy-bargy, stay, get your beauty snooze.
- 睡个美容觉 - 好了 我们走
- Beauty sleep. - Right, let's go.
你好
Hello.
我能留下来 或者我就看着你睡觉
I can stay. Or I could just watch you sleep.
为什么你...
Why are you...?
西奥
Theo!
我的动物学小伙伴
My companion in zoology.
- 早上好 - 早上好
- Kalimera. - Kalimera.
我给你带了些蜂虻
I've brought you these bee flies.
其他人都不知道这是蜜蜂还是苍蝇
They can't decide if they are bees or flies.
但不要告诉他们 这就是苍蝇
Don't tell them, but they are flies.
你能把这兴奋劲分一半到其他学习上吗
Could you show half that excitement for your other studies?
我想说一件事 在康多斯老妈的农场里
I hesitate to mention it, but Mama Kondos up at her farm...
鲁格勒斯雅的姨妈
Lugaretzia's auntie.
她有六只小狗宝宝了
she has six new puppies.
- 好棒 - 不
- Yes! - No.
不要再养宠物了 去给西奥倒杯茶吧 格里
No more pets. Go and make Theo some tea, please, Gerry.
在岛上定居的感觉怎么样
How are you settling in to the island?
科孚很棒 西奥
Corfu is wonderful, Theo.
如果我们的钱到账
Or it would be had our funds arrived
孩子们能多帮帮忙 就更棒了
and the children were more helpful.
什么都得省吃俭用 还有...
It's all so frugal and...
男人的问题
Well, male.
莱斯利 去打猎
Leslie! Foraging!
正准备去呢
I'm going.
我想念有女伴的日子 西奥
I miss the company of women, Theo.
派翠迪斯太太挺好的 你们肯定谈得来
Mrs Patridis is nice. You'd get on.
我的希腊语不行 我还在数数呢
My Greek isn't up to it. I'm still on the numbers.
不 她是英国人 嫁给了派翠迪斯医生
No, she's English. Married to Dr.Patridis.
你可以去拜访一下
You should drop in on her.
早安 亲爱的
Morning, darling.
我刚才看见拉里和两个朋友
I saw your Larry and two friends just now
在镇上的雅尼酒吧里
in Yanni's Bar in town.
扳手腕呢
Arm wrestling.
那一定是马克斯和唐纳德了
That will be Max and Donald.
如果你仔细想想
If you think about it,
法西斯主义的创始人 意大利法西斯党首领及独裁者 掌权期间 1922-1945
墨索里尼确实很坏 但他其实是个傻子
Mussolini is bad enough but he's essentially a nincompoop.
纳粹德国元首兼第二次世界大战的发动者
反倒是希特勒...
Whereas Hitler is...
不要再说他了 唐纳德
No more about him, Donald.
- 我在度假呢 - 你什么时候不在度假
- I'm on holiday! - When are you not on holiday?
- 你好 马戈 - 你们在这干嘛呢
- Hello, Margo. - What are you all doing here?
唐纳德觉得这是上天的安排
Donald thinks we were put here by God.
马克斯则觉得这是宿命
Max is more of a Determinist.
- 让我... - 你是说去酒吧吧
- Let me... - You mean in the bar.
我们正醉醺醺地胡扯呢
We're maundering drunkedly.
早上好 马戈
Guten Morgen, Margo.
你好吗
Wie geht's?
不 我真的喜欢德语
No, seriously. I love German.
还有德国人
And Germans.
德国歌剧家 作曲家
瓦格纳
Wagner.
瓦格纳歌剧
我们可以雇个船去雅典看《纽伦堡的名歌手》
I can hire a boat to take us to see Die Meistersinger in Athens.
那你还是拔了我的脚趾吧
I'd rather pull out my toes.
他是指脚趾甲
He means toenails.
我又没邀请你 马克斯
I wasn't inviting you, Max.
马吵吵
Margy-bargy.
你很漂亮
You are very nice.
但是... 拒绝
But... no.
我需要找棵树
I need to lie down.
躺一下
Under a tree.
找棵橄榄树
En olivenbaum.
但是亨利八世想要离婚
But Henry the Eighth wanted a divorce
因为他特别希望继承人是男的
because he was desperate for a male heir.
所以他买了只巨鹰
So he bought a huge eagle,
和一只猴子 一起去见了教皇
and a monkey, and he took them to see the Pope.
- 真的吗 - 当然没有
- Did he really? - Of course he didn't.
格里 专心点
Gerry, concentrate.
你需要学习
You need an education.
即使当个动物园管理员也是要学历的
Even zookeepers need an education.
我每天都在学新的东西
I'm learning new things every day.
我就喜欢待在外面
I just enjoy being outside.
我才不想坐在
I am not going to sit outside
外面的地上被虫吃了
on the terrace being eaten alive by bugs.
- 这不会带来霉运吗... - 不会
- Isn't it bad luck... - No.
于是亨利八世对教皇没了耐心 所以...
So Henry the Eighth lost patience with the Pope so...
他叫我马吵吵
He called me Margy-bargy!
他觉得我是傻瓜
He thinks I'm a buffoon.
亲爱的
Oh, darling!
Darling! Oh.
格里 别把乌龟放桌上
Gerry, tortoises off the table.
汤可能有点淡
Soup's a bit thin, I'm afraid.
我丢了一堆东西下去 都是些...
I had to cobble it together from...
你们不用知道
You don't need to know.
马戈 不要阴沉个脸
Oh, Margo. Don't be unhappy.
他们怎么说的来着
You know what they say.
你得亲吻很多青蛙才能...
You have to kiss a lot of frogs...
frog是法国人的蔑称
马克斯是德国人 不是法国人
Max is German, not French.
不 我不是这意思...
No, I didn't mean...
我都没亲过他
I've never kissed him and
我也亲不到他了 因为在他眼里我一文不值
I never will because, to him, I am nothing.
我就像... 跳蚤一样
I am... a flea.
你是跳蚤的话 就能跳160英尺高
If you were a flea, you'd be able to jump 160 feet high.
不说其他的 别跟马克斯一样疯就行
Apart from anything, like Max being a maniac,
你才十六岁
you are only 16.
他不是疯子
He's not a maniac!
什么东西闻起来这么香
Mm, something smells good!
- 不 等等 是我 - 一个愉快的德雷尔家成员
- Oh, no, wait. That's me. - A cheerful Durrell.
我们可没什么好高兴的
We don't get many of those round these parts.
亚历克西娅摆弄着草帽的样子...
Alexia was mucking around with this straw hat and...
天啊 她太有趣了
Oh, God, she's so funny.
她用鱿鱼丝给我们
She made us these rings out
各编了个戒指 说我们是灵魂伴侣
of a squid because she said we're soul mates.
对不起
Sorry.
你用什么煮的 野草吗
Mm, what did you make this out of, weeds?
是的
Yes, I did.
我今天又去了一次银行
So I went to the bank again today.
还是没有钱的影子
Still no sign of our money.
天哪 太安静了 拉里去哪了
God, it's quiet. Where's Larry?
他应该和唐纳德还有马克斯出去了
Presumably he's off with Donald and Max.
此处为模仿马克斯的口音
快些 没有香槟我会死的
Ah! Qvick! I vill die vizzout champagne!
你知道她爱上了马克斯
You know she's in love with Max.
是吗
Is she?
- 为什么 - 对她友好点
- Why? - Be kind to her.
你也是 格里 鼓励她
You too, Gerry. Encourage her.
单恋是很痛苦的
Unrequited love can be so painful.
我可不知道
I wouldn't know.
每天都要"peenygrip"
Bloody peenygrip all day.
起床 所有的人都给我出去找吃的
Wake up! I want you all out foraging!
食物 能卖钱的
For food, something to sell!
或者找个工作
Or a job!
任何事情
Anything!
我们要食物 否则就坐下趟船回家
We need food or we are all on the next boat home!
早上好
Morning.
起来
Get up.
- 你好 是康多斯老妈吗 - 是的
- Yia sas. Mama Kondos? - Nai.
我是格里
My name is Gerry.
你好 格里
Yia sou, Gerry.
谢谢 我朋友说你有些小狗
Thank you. My friend Theo says you have puppies.
小狗 是的
Puppies. Yes.
过来
Come.
嗨
Hello.
- 我能收养一只吗 - 可以 但要过一阵
- Can I have one? - Yes, soon.
它们现在需要妈妈
Need Mummy now.
我喜欢他
I love him.
她
Her.
他
Him?
你好 我是路易莎·德雷尔
Hello, I'm Louisa Durrell.
你好 我丈夫恐怕外出访客了
Oh, hello. I'm afraid my husband is out on a call.
不 我不是来找医生的
No, I don't need a doctor.
那你需要什么
Oh, right. What do you need?
我听说你是英国人
I was told you're English.
- 是的 - 我也是
- Yes, I am. - So am I!
我们多幸运
Lucky us!
不是说我们幸运 我的意思是...
I mean, not lucky, lucky us. I mean...
关于如何在这生存下去
I was hoping you might have some advice
我希望你能给我些建议
on how to survive here.
# 我想成为... #
Well, I wanna be...
# 她会不会来 让我带你沉醉在爱的摇篮 #
Won't she come and let me rock you in my cradle of love?
这就是觅食
Now, that is foraging.
茶 我喜欢
Ah, tea. Lovely.
其实是用食用淀粉冲的
In fact, it's salep.
由兰花的块茎碾成的
Made from the tubers of orchids.
这在伯恩茅斯可是会让人惊讶的啊
Well, that would raise a few eyebrows in Bournemouth.
这也是我喜欢它的原因之一
Yes, one reason why I like it.
正如我所说的
That's exactly the kind of thing I say.
你的家乡是 伯恩茅斯吗
Is that where you're from, Bournemouth?
不是 只是我丈夫过世后
No, no. We just ended up there
从那里搬出来了而已
after my husband died.
我们都没有适应那里 所以就搬过来了
We didn't really fit in, so I moved us all here.
我就是觉得英格兰很冷
I always found England so frigid.
我的孩子们都水深火热
Well, my children were struggling.
拉里想当名作家
Larry wanted to be a writer
却成了汉普郡最糟糕的房地产经纪人
but was the worst estate agent in Hampshire.
而马戈正在变成了一个傻瓜
While Margo was turning into a twit.
好吧
Right.
格里讨厌学校
Gerry loathes school.
莱斯利想冲一切会动的东西开枪
Leslie wanted to shoot anything that moved.
他们现在好点了吗
And that's getting better now?
你怎么样
What about you?
我就是喜欢这里
Oh, I just love it here.
尤其是没有一堆背井离乡的英国人
Especially as there are no hordes of English exiles
他们一边喝杜松子酒 还一边谈论珍珠项链
drinking G&Ts and rattling their pearls.
- 吃些卡布尼 - 谢谢
- Have some kabuni. - Oh, thank you.
这叫什么来着
Remind me again what it is.
当地的甜点 羊肉汤加丁香混合而成
A local dessert. Ram's broth combined with cloves.
你需要配些甜汁
You need the sweet sauce with it.
抱歉 我太饿了
Oh, sorry. I'm starving!
是的 羊的味道上来了
Oh, yes. There's the sheep coming through.
你是那种身在国外
You're one of those Brits
也会想念岩皮饼和卷布丁的英国人
abroad who wants rock cakes and roly-poly.
不 才不是
No, no, not at all.
这就是流亡者和移民之间的区别
Such a difference between expats and committed migrants.
你可以骄傲地做一个英国人
You can be proud of being British and miss it
怀念它的同时享受现在的新家
yet still embrace your new home.
这就像你结婚了
Is that like being married,
却还念着你的前男友
but still fancying your old boyfriend?
至少前男友
At least old boyfriends
不会和他们一样 把钱都弄丢了
don't lose our money as they have done here.
这愚蠢的科孚 没让你一来
Stupid Corfu. Not letting
就立即把这买下来
you come and instantly and buy up our island.
我没想买下它
I don't want to buy it up.
我只是厌倦了像乞丐一样生活
I'm just tired of living like beggars.
我... 不会占用你太多时间
Well, I... I won't take up any more of your time.
- 你好 - 你好
- Yiasas! - You too.
你需要去多找些食物
You must go and find more food.
不 下次再说吧
No, another time.
我妈妈会搞定的
My mother will sort something out.
她很勇敢的
She is very plucky.
我一直按你说的在找食物
I've been foraging like you said.
我采了所有的浆果
And I've picked all these berries.
你是不是吃了一点
Did you eat any at all?
- 一点都没吃 - 很好
- Not really. - Oh, good.
我去了康多斯老妈的家
I went to Mama Kondos' house.
格里 我告诉过你
Gerry, I told you
如果我不带一只回来 谁知道会发生什么
Who knows what will happen to the puppies if I don't take one?
我们怎么喂它 我们连自己都要养不活了
How will we feed a puppy? We can barely feed ourselves.
它可以吃些浆果
It can live off the berries.
亲爱的 小狗不吃浆果
Dogs don't eat berries, darling.
- 罗杰就吃 - 罗杰一直有些奇怪
- Roger does. - Roger's always been a bit odd.
我找到了一些可以卖的东西
I've got something we can sell!
我在马路上找到的 是个古董
I found it by the road. It's antique.
农场来自... 瓦西里
Farm of... Vasilli.
瓦西里农场
So, Vasilli Farm.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们是新来的
Er... We're new here!
没有人要说话
Nobody say anything.
希望能长出该死的豆茎
Let's hope a magic bloody beanstalk comes up.
格里
Gerry! Gerry!
我们来送小狗了
Ferame to koulouki!
- 你好 - 你好
- Kalimera. - Kalimera.
这是给格里的
This is for Gerry.
格里的小狗
Gerry's puppy.
你好
Hello. Hello.
停下 就是这
Stop! This is it!
和我们在德国说的一样...
Or as we say in Germany...
- 什么 - 不 没区别
- What? - No, we say the same.
你消失几天了
You've been gone for days.
快乐是需要时间和承诺的
Well, fun takes time and commitment.
你知道有一个甜瓜节吗
Did you know there was a melon festival?
你知道我需要帮助 拉里
You knew I needed help, Larry.
在我的朋友面前 能不让我难堪吗
Would you mind not embarrassing me in front of my friends?
抱歉 德雷尔夫人 我们忘了时间
I am sorry, Mrs Durrell. We lost track of time.
甜瓜节真得不错
It was a really good melon festival.
他是个很好的玩伴
He is excellent company.
拉里 模仿一下那个在酒吧里
Larry, Do your imitation of a man
招呼服务生的人吧
trying to be served in a crowded bar!
- 现在不是时候 - 三瓶威士忌 请
- Maybe not now. - Three whiskeys, bitte!
请
Please!
有点像 但是更搞笑
Like that but more funny!
好吧
Ok, ok.
我们水深火热的时候 你却在外面快活
I am tired of you living it up while we struggle.
- 帮下我们 - 我在帮啊
- Help us. - I was helping.
少了一个人吃饭啊
By being one less mouth to feed.
这是你能想到的最好的办法吗
Is that the best you can come up with?
我把短篇小说寄到英格兰了
I sent my short story to England.
- 能赚不少稿费 - 不 不会的
- That will bring us a tidy sum. - No. No, it won't.
即使发表了 也没多少钱
Even if it's accepted, you'll earn a pittance.
- 她怎么了 - 她爱上了马克斯
- What's wrong with her? - She's in love with Max.
- 不可能的 - 那给她点建议啊
- No, that won't work. - Well, give her some advice.
你不是总说自己多么成熟老练吗
You're always talking about how worldly-wise you are.
我...
I...
可以给提点关于爱情的建议
gather you need some advice about love.
- 不需要 - 我这就说
- No. - Well, I'm here now.
你还是忘记马克斯吧
Obviously you should forget Max,
你配不上他 找唐纳德吧
who is out of your league, and go for Donald.
别闷闷不乐地在房子边逛边想他了
Stop moping about the house and think about him,
可怜的家伙
poor sod.
唐纳德非常可靠 是个好对象
Donald will be such a reliable companion for you.
- 她现在应该好多了 - 真的吗
- I think she'll be all right now. - Is that it?
这就是你友好的建议
Is that your friendly advice?
你没说过要友好啊
You didn't say friendly.
她不需要一个可靠的对象
She doesn't need a reliable companion.
鼓励她 她很漂亮 很聪明
I meant tell her she's beautiful. Or clever.
难道就她一个人有情感问题吗 我们呢
So she's unhappy in love. Aren't we all?
我在怀念南希 你倒是没人可想
I'm missing Nancy. You've got nobody.
我在想你们啊
I've got all of you!
而且我努力让大家度过这周
And I am just trying to make it through the week!
我已经告诉其他人了
I've told the others
让你们都出去找食物或是钱
I want you all out foraging for food or money
- 我会和马克斯要钱的 - 不 不行
- I'll ask Max for money. - Oh, no, you won't.
- 你没有自尊心吗 - 没有
- Have you no pride? - No.
反正我也犯了不少"七宗罪"
I've got most of the seven deadly sins,
但你说的这一宗有点傻
but that one seems a bit silly.
我们不需要施舍
We don't want charity.
我们是一个足智多谋且独立的家庭
We are a resourceful and independent family.
好吧
Right!
这就对了 来啊 朝你妈妈开枪
Oh, that's right. Go on, shoot your mother!
那就能解决所有的问题了
That will solve all your problems!
我要去打猎
I'm going hunting.
你想把我们变成原始的拾荒者
You want to turn us into medieval scavengers.
拉里 你不会射击
Larry, you don't know how to shoot.
能有多难呢
How hard can it be?
真的很疼
It really hurts, you know!
你应该试试生孩子
You should try childbirth.
你应该试试打仗
You should try war.
其实第一次世界大战英国的女性非常英勇 这里在讽刺拉里每天寻欢作乐
是啊 上次战争的时候
Yes, because us women spent the last war
女人们都在傻笑和购物
giggling and shopping
行了 拉里
Come on, Larry.
你那根本就不算疼
You know you take even moderate pain badly.
敏感一点不好吗
Suddenly it's bad to be sensitive?
莱斯利 你能安慰一下马戈吗
Leslie, would you please have a kind word with Margo?
她失恋了
She's an emotional wreck.
等一下 给你一些指导
Wait, some guidelines.
不要提到你自己的幸福爱情生活
Don't mention your own happy love life.
不要告诉她 振作起来
Don't tell her to pull herself together.
就... 就想想你能说些什么
Just... Just think about what you're saying.
- 好吧 我过会儿再来 - 没事 进来吧
- It's fine, I'll come back later. - No, come in.
你可能会觉得拉里快死了
Larry's at death's door, you'd think.
提醒你一下 一般人是不会意识到
Mind you, your average layman doesn't realise what a punch
韦斯特利·理查兹箱锁式模型枪的后坐力有多大
the Westley Richards Boxlock model packs.
没错
No.
妈妈说你在恋爱问题上需要一些建议
Mum says you need some advice about your love problem.
减减肥吧 大多数男人不喜欢太胖的女生
I'd say lose some weight. Most men don't go for fat girls.
从树林带回来的午餐
Lunch from the woods.
好样的 亲爱的
Well done, darling.
这些... 吃... 死
These.... eat... dead.
去看看今早来了什么
Look what arrived for you this morning.
- 我的小狗 - 康多斯老妈送来的
- My puppy! - From Mama Kondos.
不是这一只
It's the wrong one.
希望她还没有把我的那一只送人
I hope she hasn't given mine away!
我要把这只送回去 然后换过来
I'm going to take it back and swap it!
莱斯利
Leslie! Leslie!
去找斯皮罗斯
Go and get Spiros!
快去
Run!
咱们快走
Let's go now!
讽刺土耳其人一出汗身上体味很重
- 他现在就像个土耳其人 - 他怎么了
- He's sweating like a Turk. - What's wrong with him?
他摔倒的时候 可能内脏破裂了
Maybe he ruptured an internal organ when he fell.
谁是科孚最好的医生
Who is the very best doctor on Corfu?
派翠迪斯医生
Dr Patridis.
- 因为他是岛上唯一的医生 - 什么
- Because he's the only doctor. - What?
- 去年死了两个医生 - 这似乎不太妙啊
- Two doctors died last year. - That's not a good sign, is it?
你认识派翠迪斯医生吗
Do you know Dr Patridis?
不认识 但我见过他妻子
No, I've met his wife.
他的脸色不太好
I don't like the looks of him.
斯皮罗斯 这样开拉里很不舒服
Spiros! This isn't good for Larry.
很抱歉 芝加哥的路要好很多
I apologise. The roads were better in Chicago.
- 你好 - 我最大的儿子病了
- Oh, hello. - It's my eldest boy.
我丈夫去了莱夫卡扎 几天后才回来
I'm afraid my husband is on Lefkada for a few days.
你居然允许科孚
The only qualified doctor on Corfu
唯一有资质的医生离开这座岛
and you've allowed him to leave the island?
求求你帮帮我们
Please help us!
带他进来吧
Bring him in.
应该是他的阑尾 突然的压力会导致其破裂
I think it's his appendix. Sudden pressure can rupture it.
- 我们能做些什么 - 我不知道
- What can we do? - I don't know.
- 亲爱的 - 有人吗
- Darling. - Hello!
有人吗
Hello!
大家好
Hello, everyone.
- 我听说了发生的事 - 西奥多尔学过医
- I heard what happened. - Theodore studied medicine.
- 谢天谢地 - 只学过一两个月
- Oh, thank goodness. - Only for a month or two.
虽然是出于自己的喜好 一直在自学
Though I've carried on studying for my own satisfaction.
应该腹部遭到创伤造成了阑尾炎
Suspected appendicitis following abdominal trauma.
如果他就躺在那里
If he just lies there and
不叫了 会没事的吧
shuts up for once, will he be all right?
不 要赶在破裂之前 马上把它取出来
No, it needs to be cut out immediately before it bursts.
谁能做这个手术
Who can do that?
- 我可以试试 - 不行
- I can have a go. - No.
- 不行 - 不行
- No. - No.
我没有护士的资质
I'm not a qualified nurse
但之前帮忙上过麻醉剂
but I've helped with anaesthetic before.
帮他做好准备
Get him ready.
请随便找些这方面知识的书
Please find any books on the subject.
他这是去哪儿了
Where's he going?
对不起 但我答应过你的兄弟
I'm sorry, but I promised your brother.
别担心 我也会留下你的
Don't worry. I'll keep you too.
你好
Yiasas!
是你啊 格里
Yia sou, Gerry.
谢谢你把小狗送过去
Thank you for bringing the puppy.
但是我想要另一只
But I need another one.
它们还在你这里吗
Do you still have them?
你怎么可以这样 你不觉得这很残忍吗
How dare you? Can't you see that's so cruel?
如果有人把你活埋了呢
What if someone buried you alive?
把你的女儿活埋了呢
Or your daughters?
那么...
So...
我听说你喜欢上了个德国男孩
I hear you are crazy for a German boy.
但是他不喜欢你
But he's not crazy for you.
我们不需要谈论这个的
We don't need to talk about it.
当然要谈 对你有好处
No, it's good.
能让你分散注意力
It takes your mind off your brother.
我给她提建议了
I gave her my advice.
她不接受
She didn't like it.
你知道我的建议是什么吗
You know my advice?
胖一点 男人不喜欢太瘦的女孩
Get fatter. Men don't like skinny girls.
我都不知道自己为什么这么心烦
I don't know why I'm getting upset.
他真的很烦人的
He's really annoying.
这是每个家长最担忧的事
It's every parent's biggest fear.
你的孩子正在受苦
Your child being in pain.
你没有孩子吗
You don't have children?
没有
No.
那你倒是不用考虑这些了
Well, you've saved yourself all this.
你儿子的身体很强壮
The body is surprisingly strong.
有人吗
Hello!
有人在家吗
Anyone home?
我们带拉里去找派翠迪斯医生了 情况不太好
爱你的 妈妈
没关系的 待在这
It's all right. Stay here.
我很快就会回来的 我保证 好吗
I'll be home soon. Promise. OK.
罗杰
Roger!
这是我朋友斯文 和我想的一样
This is my friend Sven. As I hoped,
他之前做过手术
he has done this operation before.
做过一次 给动物做的
Once. On an animal.
从解剖学层面来说 区别不大
In anatomical terms, there is little difference.
结合派翠迪斯太太的经验
Between Mrs Patridis's experience,
和我的书本知识 还有斯文...
my book knowledge, and Sven's...
斯文屠宰的是一只山羊
Sven's butchery of the odd goat.
这是我儿子
This is my son.
恐怕没有其他选择了
I'm afraid there isn't much choice.
我们不能送他离开这座岛吗
Can't we get him off the island?
去雅典或是意大利 一定有船过去的
To Athens or Italy. There must be a boat.
顺利的情况下 坐船需要十八个小时
18 hours away, and that's if you're lucky.
太晚了 这样会害死他的
It's too late, and the journey would kill him.
很遗憾 德雷尔太太
I'm sorry, Mrs Durrell,
但是如果不这样 情况会更糟糕
it is this or the worst will happen.
我还是有信心的
I'm very hopeful.
他们可能想和我们要钱
They're probably going to want money from us.
- 拉里的手术钱 - 我们需要去找工作了
- For Larry's operation. - We're going to have to get jobs.
真的吗
Oh, really?
天啊 是马克斯
Oh, God, it's Max.
我应该怎么做
What must I do?
对了 努力看起来瘦一点
Oh, yes. Try and look thin.
我们的司机从另一个司机那里听说
Our driver heard from another
- 拉里生病了 - 你们不能进去
- driver that Larry's sick. - You can't go in.
他们正在给拉里做手术
They're cutting him open.
可怜的拉里
Poor Larry.
你好 马戈
Hello, Margo.
你好 唐纳德
Hello, Donald.
你好 马戈
Oh... Hello, Margo.
我很遗憾拉里发生了这样的事
I... I'm sorry about Larry.
拉里像我们想的一样好 亲爱的
Larry is as well as can be expected, darling.
嗨 拉里
Hello, Larry.
因为麻醉 他要过一会儿才能醒
He won't be out of the anaesthetic for a while.
不管发生什么 谢谢你
Whatever happens, thank you.
任何人都会这么做的
Anybody would have done the same.
不 其他人不会的
No, they wouldn't.
我应该回去看看病人了
I... I'd better go and check on the patient.
如果你不介意的话 我要赶快走了
If you'll excuse me, I have to rush off.
我的猪喂到一半就出来了 真讨厌
Leaving my pig only half-fed. Hates that.
- 可以去我那儿转转 - 一定会的
- Do drop by and see me. - I will.
我会去的
I'd like that.
我会弹手风琴
I play the accordion, you know.
这是挑战吗
Is that a threat?
- 你心情好吗 - 你干了什么
- Are you in a good mood? - What have you done?
我去找康多斯老妈拿回了正确的小狗时
I went to Mama Kondos to take the wrong puppy back
她正想把剩下的小狗都活埋了
and she was burying all the other puppies alive.
不是吧
Oh, no.
我及时救下了它们
So I saved them just in time.
- 她人很好 但这样做不好 - 好吧
- She's nice, but that was a terrible thing. - Well...
他们这里做事的方法不一样 格里
They do things differently here, Gerry.
我把它们都带走了
I had to take them all away.
所以现在我们要养六只小狗了
So now we have to keep all six puppies.
好吧...
Well...
好吧 你可以留下两只
All right, you can keep two.
- 谢谢 - 其他的你得给它们找到主人
- Thank you. - You have to find homes for the others.
- 斯皮罗斯养一只 - 不
- Spiros is having one. - No.
我自己掌管我的家
I'm in charge of my house.
养动物要么是为了种地
Animals are for the farm only.
要么用来吃
And the dinner table.
狗不行 我们不吃狗
Not dogs. We don't eat dogs.
除了热狗
Except hotdogs!
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
我让拉里宿醉未醒就带着枪出去
I sent Larry off with a gun and a hangover.
我什么时候才能学会只要他们在身边就好
When will I learn just to enjoy their company?
德雷尔太太 你是个完美的母亲
Mrs. Durrells, you are the perfect mother.
- 谢谢你 斯皮罗斯 - 别说傻话
- Thank you, Spiros. - No bullshit.
我得去开车 很快回来
I have to drive my car. I'll be back soons.
斯皮罗斯
Spiros!
- 早上好 - 早上好
- Kalimera! - Kalimera.
早上好 美国佬
Kalimera ipa!
他们都是好人
They are good people!
拜托 拉里 说点什么
Oh, come on, Larry. Say something.
你不总是说个不停吗
You always say something.
拉里 情况如何
So Larry, how's tricks?
让他别嚷了
Tell him to stop shouting.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这茶里面有什么特殊成分吗
Does this tea have some sort of special root in it?
没有 就是普通红茶
No, normal tea.
还有饼干
And biscuits.
好吧 也许我内心还是有一点怀念英国的
All right, perhaps there's a bit of me that misses England.
在科孚镇上有个人
Oh! There's a man in Corfu
他认识一个女人能买到阿华田
Town who knows a woman who can get Ovaltine.
不用了 谢谢
No, thank you.
我在外国时 一般只吃当地食品
When I'm in a foreign country, I only like to eat local food.
不好意思 神父 非常抱歉
Signomi, Pater. Signomi.
德雷尔太太 我去了银行 把你们的钱要来了
Mrs. Durrells, I went to the bank and got your money.
谢谢你 斯皮罗斯
Oh, thank you, Spiros.
你对我 对我们全家真好
You are so good to me. To all of us.
你们是英国人 我最喜欢的民族啊
You're English, my favourite peoples.
你没冲着银行职员
You didn't shout at the bank clerk,
- 大喊大叫吧 - 我干嘛要大吼大叫
- did you? - Why would I shout?
你确实会冲着人大吼大叫 斯皮罗斯
Well, you do shout at people, Spiros.
什么
What?
喝香槟吗 斯皮罗斯
Champagne, Spiros?
- 好的 - 敬我们
- Sure. - Yiamas!
拉里
Larry.
拉里 我们的钱到了
Larry, our money's arrived.
不过是你的钱
But it's yours.
短篇故事的稿费
For your short story.
干得好
Well done.
我是个合格的作家了
I'm a proper writer.
我有个建议
I have some advice.
天哪 你也来 格里
Oh, God, not you too, Gerry.
我必须得劝你 妈妈说了
Sorry, I have to. Mum said.
我一直在考虑这件事
I've been thinking about this.
黑寡妇蜘蛛
The black widow spider
会摆动腹部来吸引它选中的雄性
shakes its bottom to attract its chosen mate.
或许你对马克斯也可以试试
So perhaps you could do that to Max.
- 你要去试试看吗 - 不 格里
- Are you going to do it? - No, Gerry.
其实...
In fact...
我永远再也不爱了
I'm giving up on love for ever!
不爱了
on love for ever!
欢迎
Welcome.
拉里醒了
Larry has woken up.
- 他的情况在好转 - 我很高兴
- He's on the mend. - I'm so glad.
我尝到甜头了
Getting the taste for it now.
下一步就可以做颅脑手术了
Think I'm ready for some brain surgery.
我才发觉我对你一无所知
I realised I don't know anything about you.
你懂我们这些斯堪的纳维亚人
You know us Scandinavians.
我们喜欢保持神秘
We like to be a little enigmatic.
你为什么来科孚
What brings you to Corfu?
毫无疑问 和你一样
Same as you, no doubt.
被古文明所吸引 荷马的故乡
Lure of an ancient civilisation. Land of Homer.
而在斯德哥尔摩
And you can't take your shirt
你连脱下衬衣都会被冻伤
off in Stockholm without getting frostbite.
不啊 在伯恩茅斯生活也一样
No. No, I had the same problem in Bournemouth.
斯文太太在吗
Is there a Mrs. Sven?
不存在 德雷尔先生呢
No. Is there a Mr. Durrell?
也不在
No. No.
曾经在 后来他走了
Not any more.
我无意冒犯 也不想妄加猜测
I didn't want to offend you and I also didn't want to assume,
但是我得付给您拉里的手术钱
but I must pay you for Larry's operation.
我不知道多少才合适...
I'm not sure how much...
不必了 你真是扫兴
No, you just spoilt it all.
马戈
Oh, Margo.
很不容易 不是吗
It's not easy, is it?
阿华田
对不起 对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
对不起
Sorry.
不行
No!
不要 把它们拿走
No, take them away.
我从一帮赤脚医生的手术里活下来
I did not survive a major operation carried out by hobbyists
可不是为了吃金橘的
just to eat more kumquats.
金橘到处都是
They're very plentiful actually.
靠灌木丛里长的那些就能活得很好了
You can live quite nicely just from what you find in hedgerows.
他们为什么要把桌子放在海里
Why are they putting the table in the sea?
这样比较凉快 莱斯利的主意
To keep us cool. It was Leslie's idea.
他提出来的主意不多 所以别讽刺他
He doesn't have many, so please be kind about this one.
你不打算谢我吗
So aren't you going to thank me?
这话怎么讲
Where do I start?
- 那么多事情呢 - 谢我把稿费给了你
- There's so much. - For giving you my story money.
我觉得你的抚恤金没这么快到
I don't think your pension is going to arrive any time soon.
所以你要靠我
So you'll be sponging off
这个职业作家养活了
me forever now I'm a professional author.
把你的话变成文字 好吗
Use your powers for good, won't you?
别用来嘲笑家人 变成讨人厌的作家
Don't be one of those awful writers who pokes fun at his family.
别担心 我忙着写性爱呢
Don't worry. I'll be too busy writing about sex.
像我这样的艺术家 需要打破世俗的常规
Artists like me need to live outside the normal rules of society.
再实际一点就是我需要经常喝醉
Which in practice means getting drunk. A lot.
你要去哪 回来
Where are you going? Come back!
- 把我推过去 - 你的伤口不能沾水
- Wheel me! - Can't get your wound wet.
- 你只能待在岸上了 - 什么
- Have to stay on the beach. - What?
- 不行 - 会涨潮吗
- No! - Is the tide coming in?
不会 这里是地中海 潮水很小
No, it's Mediterranean. It's only a small one.
- 我检查过了 现在是退潮 - 我很孤单
- I checked. It's going out. - I'm lonely!
鲁格勒斯雅 能把那个...
Lugaretzia, would you please pass the...
那个奇怪的水果递给我吗
the strange fruit?
鲁格勒斯雅 你不可能一直不理格里
Lugaretzia, you can't ignore Gerry for ever.
尤其是你到现在还不理拉里
Particularly as you're still ignoring Larry.
他对我的姨妈大吼大叫
He shout at my auntie.
她说的有道理
She's got a point.
她姨妈那样做太残忍了
She was being cruel.
我们不能批评别人的传统习俗
We mustn't criticise other people's customs and traditions.
如果是可怕的事情 就要批评
We can if they do horrible things.
他在喊什么
What's he shouting?
- "混蛋" - 什么
- "Arsehole". - What?
鲁格勒斯雅教他的
Lugaretzia taught him it.
她告诉他那是"你好"的意思
She told him it means hello.
啊嘿
Ahoy there!
- 我们要走了 - 你们要去哪
- We are leaving! - Where are you going?
不知道
Don't know!
那边吧
That way!
保重 拉里
Get better, Larry!
再见 马戈
Goodbye, Margo!
- 再见 马戈 - 你不说声再见吗
- Goodbye, Margo! - Aren't you going to say goodbye?
马戈 到船上来喝一杯
Margo, come aboard for a drink!
继续 你们还有什么建议
Go on, then. Give me your advice.
- 不提了 - 不提什么建议了 亲爱的
- Never again. - Never again, darling.
- 不 - 来啊 马戈
- No. - Come on, Margo!
来啊 还等什么
Come on! What are you waiting for?
我来了
I'm coming!
- 加油 - 马戈 加油
- Keep coming! - Margo, keep going!
- 游啊 - 加油
- Swim! - Come on!
涨潮了
The tide is rising, you know.
- 没有吧 - 不 就是在涨潮
- No, it isn't. - No, it is.
确实在涨潮 走吧
Yeah, it is actually. Come on.
欢迎上船
Welcome onboard.
年轻人的爱情啊
Young love.
那老年人的爱情呢
What about old love?
如果你说的是我 我可不老
If you mean me, I'm not old.
而且别再给我介绍了
And don't start that again.
拜托 你和那个芬兰人
Come on, you and the Flying Finn.
- 他是瑞典人 - 一回事
- He's from Sweden. - The same thing.
藏起来我都能嗅到暧昧的味道
I know naked lust when it's in the room.
你个蠢货
You are an idiot.
回头见 再见
See you later! Bye-bye!
她会回来的吧
She is coming back, isn't she?
马戈 亲爱的 回来
Margo! Darling, come back!
他跟你不合适 马戈
He's not right for you! Margo!